This time will be different.
Subaru?
What's wrong?
Can you move?
Can you talk?
[sighs]
[gasps]
Emilia.
[BEATRICE]
Emilia isn't the only one
who was worried about you.
Oh!
Ah!
What's that look for,
I suppose?
It's almost as if you can't
believe the adorable Betty
is standing right before you.
Beatrice!
Oh, Beatrice!
What the heck?
This is too sudden, I suppose.
It's just you--
you really--
you have a face that makes
me feel at ease and happy.
It's so cute that I
feel like I'm back home.
I could fall in love.
You know, I really don't
want to believe you meant that
as a compliment, so I won't.
Please, Subaru, don't mess
with us right when you wake up.
We still don't even
know why you passed out.
So when you act
like that, you--
Subaru?
[crying]
[emotional music]
♪ ♪
What's wrong, I suppose?
It's all right.
Betty will be right
here by your side.
[SUBARU cries]
♪ ♪
No need for tears, Subaru.
Just take slow, deep breaths.
Calm down.
Beatrice is here.
And so am I.
We've got you.
[crying]
♪ ♪
[theme music]
[singing]
♪ ♪
[SUBARU]
So that's how it is.
It seems like I
lost my memories
when I was in the archive.
This might cause a lot
of trouble for you guys,
but I appreciate all
of you bearing with me.
I know you're all really
worried about Subaru right now,
but it's important for all
of us to keep it together.
I'm sure no one feels
more anxious than he does.
It doesn't look
that way to me.
Tell me, what kind of dumb
act is this, Barusu?
This isn't an act
or something.
I'm being super
serious about telling
you all the whole truth.
And honestly, my heart's about
to explode from the anxiety.
So your acting has improved.
You think if you speak
confidently, we'll simply--
[BEATRICE] Subaru isn't the
kind of person that would hurt
us by telling such cruel lies.
You should know that as well
as anyone, I suppose.
Mm.
Oh, well, what
are we gonna do?
You're just completely
hopeless, aren't you?
[gasps]
Why the heck did
you react like that?
Seriously, you look like you
just saw a ghost or something.
Talk about rude.
[creepy noise]
Hey, Meili.
[MEILI]
Interesting.
So at the very least you
still remember my name, huh?
OK, then.
In that case,
what did you forget?
[SUBARU]
A lot, unfortunately,
I lost what they call
episodic memory.
I can still remember the names
of most people and things,
but when it comes
to experiences with them,
it gets pretty murky.
All right,
so does that include,
say, what happened yesterday?
Mm.
It does.
[JULIUS]
All of yesterday, huh?
I see.
Yes, I suppose so.
[SHAULA] Again, Master,
are you for really real?
Are you gonna keep
forgetting me over and over
until I die alone?
[ECHIDNA] Frankly, it's a bit
difficult to accept that truth,
but still, it's likely there's
a trap in this tower that
left Natsuki in this state.
I think it's important
that we tread carefully.
Mm.
The most likely place is
the archive where Emilia
and Beatrice discovered me.
I mean, it's been shady
from the beginning.
Um--
Anyway, I'm sorry I
scared you all like that.
I'm sure we all need a bit
of time to process everything,
so let's take a break.
I'll make myself useful
and go with Ram to fetch
water in the meantime.
Let's get it done, Ram.
You looked like you
were just about to ask
me to accompany you anyway.
So lewd.
[footsteps]
OK, what was the idea
behind that ridiculous farce?
Ram, it's really true
that I lost my memory.
It isn't a lie, or a grift,
or an evil plot.
Mm.
My memory is gone.
I remember names
and relationships
and not a whole lot
more than that.
Knock it off.
All I know is that we
all came to this tower
to get back a bunch
of stuff that we lost
and that we need to pass some
exams, but otherwise, nothing.
My motive is--
Shut up, Barusu.
No more.
And Rem too. I--
Barusu!
Ah!
[clattering]
What are you playing at?
What is this?
What's with all these
ridiculous lies?
I'm not lying to you.
So you're telling me
to just trust you blindly,
to believe that
you would forget Rem,
something so
unfathomably stupid?
Memories or not,
I'm getting Rem back.
[RAM]
Ah!
Who do you think you are?
Get her back?
You don't even
remember her, do you?
Barusu, you forgot Rem!
I'll still get her back,
Rem and my memories too.
All of it!
I'll do every damn
thing there is to do.
Then we'll go home.
We deserve that much at least.
After everything
we've been through,
this tower's done
a real number on us.
Barusu!
[emotional music]
Ram, I'm going to get Rem
and all of my memories back.
I'm going to need you
to help me do that.
I'm going to need
help from all of you.
You might never forgive me
for forgetting about Rem,
and I understand.
But still, I swear.
Swear what?
That I will see this through.
If I ever go back on my word,
then you can do
whatever you want to me.
After all, I was
already careless enough
to lose all of my memories.
And on top of that,
I made you cry.
It'd be my penance.
♪ ♪
Hmm.
Huh?
[slapping]
[thud]
Who's crying?
Don't be dumb.
Oh, come on!
It took a lot of courage
for me to say all that stuff.
You got yourself
all worked up.
How did that take courage?
Also, a promise from you?
Don't make me laugh.
Wait, how many promises did
I break up until yesterday?
You should be asking
how many you've kept.
That's easier to count?
Oh!
Oh, man.
This Subaru Natsuki
really is worthless, huh?
Why'd you even bring
me to this tower?
[RAM]
You butted in.
Also, you did have
a knack for running
your mouth in every situation.
We could count on you
to handle odd jobs too.
Is there anything else?
I mean, I have short
legs, my memory's bad.
And I'm also a picky eater who
doesn't know when to give up.
You had short legs,
your memory was bad,
and you were a picky eater who
didn't know when to give up.
I walked into that.
[RAM]
And
you cared
a lot about Rem.
[gasps]
Barusu, you've truly
forgotten Rem, haven't you?
Yeah.
Barusu, you're truly going
to remember her, aren't you?
Yeah, I will.
Not just Rem.
Everything else too.
[sentimental music]
Very well.
I'll allow it, I suppose.
On your feet, Barusu.
♪ ♪
[SUBARU]
I was--
Subaru Natsuki was
definitely here, wasn't he?
[RAM]
Silly.
At the moment, it's just that
he's temporarily invisible.
Like a flower buried under
a freezing blanket of snow,
he'll emerge once more when the
cruelty of winter has passed.
I'm not worried.
I'm sure that's
all there is to it.
Ha!
♪ ♪
[sighs deeply]
Last time,
and the time before that,
this place turned
into a complete disaster.
That mess will all
happen again, and soon.
I have to find a way
to stop it, no matter what,
which is why, for starters--
Ah!
Ah! Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
[sighs]
Whoa, there.
Don't you go taking
that fall in my place.
Now, why don't you
and I have a chat?
I mean, that would be murder.
You need to take
responsibility.
Responsibility
for murdering you?
Once again,
you're saying some really
weird things to me, Subaru.
I'm a professional.
So if I really wanted to kill
you, I'd do it differently.
It would have been a whole
lot easier to do it outside,
you know?
Yeah, I'm sure you had
plenty of opportunities,
but you didn't feel the need
to take them, right?
[MEILI]
You get it, which is why--
That said, you not
killing me sooner
wouldn't mean a thing if you
simply didn't have a reason
to do it until this morning.
Or should I say until sometime
after the whole chain reaction
that started last night?
[sighs]
Don't tell me.
Were you lying about the whole
losing-your-memories thing?
Oh, I see.
Was this whole thing a setup?
Don't get
the wrong idea, Meili.
No, I wasn't lying
about losing my memory.
That's why this is so serious.
I'm afraid you're losing me.
And now I have even
more questions.
But for starters,
how exactly are you planning
to finish me off here, huh?
Are you gonna push
me off these stairs
so you can get your revenge?
My mean little
beasties aren't here
to protect me
at the moment, so--
I have no intention
of killing you
or of hurting you,
for that matter.
I plan to treat you the same
way that I have been all along.
Huh?
[SUBARU]
Don't worry.
Thankfully,
I stopped your crime
before you could carry it out.
So as long as I don't go
blab about it to anyone,
we can pretend it
never happened.
Well, why would--
All right.
Now, do you understand
the situation?
Trying to do anything
to me going forward
is gonna be risky.
And if you still want to try,
then, well, let's at least
talk it over first.
If something's bothering you,
I'll lend an ear
and listen as best I can.
[sad music]
Bothering me?
If anything bothers me,
it's this situation right now.
I can't believe you.
You claim that you know
what I was trying to do.
What's with that?
You couldn't possibly!
This doesn't make any sense!
It's weird, because if you
did know, then--
It was only a spontaneous
act, just an impulsive choice.
That's the only way you know
how to deal with your problems.
You simply don't
know what else to do.
And that's through
no fault of your own
because murder is a habit.
Ah!
Stop blabbering like
you know anything!
The hell could you even
possibly know about me?
[SUBARU]
I know a lot!
[gasps]
I mean it.
I know a lot about you, Meili.
And this might sound kind
of creepy, but to be honest,
I doubt there's anyone
else in this entire world
who understands who you are
at your core better than I do.
Elsa Granhiert.
[gasps]
[SUBARU] I'd bet
that she's the reason
you tried to kill me, right?
[crying]
I won't let anyone--
Ah!
--talk as if
they understand me.
[gasps]
[eerie whoosh]
[MEILI] I think Elsa Granhiert
was an unbelievable woman.
[snarls]
[thud]
I've been told to bring
you back with me.
That means you'll be
coming home with me today.
[splash]
[eerie music]
Ah!
[growling]
[bites]
Mm.
What's wrong?
I'm rather ticklish.
Stop that.
[MEILI growls]
I'm not all that
particular about the clothing
I wear either.
But you sure do have
interesting proclivities--
[growling]
--and a temper to boot.
That so, Meili?
That is what your name is,
I assume.
It's stitched into those
rags you were wearing.
They could be someone else's.
But not having a name
to call you is inconvenient.
So you are Meili.
That's what I'm going
to call you moving forward.
[MEILI]
If you say you lost everything,
forget any of it ever existed,
it would be so easy.
And then I could teach you
everything you need to know.
After all, it's a mother's
job to shape her children
into something better.
[splat]
[whimpering]
I think Elsa Granhiert
was a detestable woman.
[ELSA]
Are you shivering?
Perhaps you're cold.
Ah!
Oh!
[bite sound]
I told you to stop doing that.
It tickles.
[MEILI]
I saw every job through.
I modeled my methods
after Elsa's.
I learned to speak properly.
I modeled my speaking
patterns after Elsa's.
I even wore clothes
without fussing.
I modeled my fashion
sense after Elsa's.
And I made sure to keep all
of that secret from her.
[wind blowing]
I think Elsa Granhiert
was a dreadful woman.
[ELSA] Meili,
could you braid my hair?
I can't be bothered.
Meili, are you listening to me?
I'm asking you to braid
my hair for me.
Yes, I know.
I heard you.
Honestly, you're such a slob.
[eerie music]
♪ ♪
Ahm!
Huh?
What are you doing?
That tickles.
Ahm!
[ELSA laughs]
You're such a funny girl.
♪ ♪
[MEILI] She was a huge
presence in my mind,
and I didn't want
her to disappear.
She was an unbelievable,
detestable, dreadful part
of my life.
No, calling it a "part"
wouldn't be right.
It wouldn't do her justice.
She was so much bigger
in existence than that.
So if that all had
to be torn apart,
if it had to be trampled on,
if Elsa Granhiert had
to be killed by someone,
then Meili Portroute--
♪ ♪
It would have been so much
better for all of us
if you had just let me end it.
[SUBARU]
Yeah, sorry.
Most people take
their shoes off
when entering someone's home.
The Natsuki family just barges
right into the hearts of others
without permission.
[stretching sound]
So was it for revenge?
I'm not really sure.
Well, let's say for a minute
that was the case.
Elsa--
Wouldn't have
wanted me to do that.
I at least know that much.
Why do you keep trying
so hard to help me?
Well, if I didn't have you,
then I'd have
an even bigger hole
in my already-pathetic
memory, you know?
Guess that's why.
Meili, I get that your own
feelings are overwhelming
and you don't know
what to do with them.
Figuring that out
won't be easy.
I doubt you'll find the answers
you're looking for right away.
So let me ease
the burden for you.
I won't let things go bad.
Or at least I'll do
everything in my power
to make sure they don't.
Of course, only as long
as that's what you want too.
[MEILI]
I can't believe that.
It's easy for you
to say whatever
you want without
a second thought.
[SUBARU] Then don't consider
it a promise with me.
Consider it a big
promise with all of us.
Huh?
[EMILIA] Yes, it's all right.
- Oh!
[EMILIA] I was listening
properly to that promise.
So that makes me a witness.
Hmm!
[SUBARU] You're seriously
a lifesaver, Emilia.
Frankly, I was pretty
sure I was a goner.
[EMILIA] Honestly, that's
what I should be saying.
I can't believe you
tried to jump with her.
I thought my heart was going
to leap right out of my chest.
[MEILI] Emilia,
you heard that, everything?
[EMILIA]
Yes.
Subaru asked me to help you out
if you ever got into trouble.
So that's what I'll do.
Oh!
Listen, Meili,
all those things Subaru said,
I believe them, so I want
you to believe him too.
Believe both of us.
We're in a tower in the middle
of an ocean of sand.
This place is too small for you
to make big decisions alone.
Once we get out of here,
you can look for your answers
in a bigger place.
Until then, we'll all
really try our best.
[crying]
Elsa's important to me.
I don't want to forget her.
I know, that's fine.
No need to make yourself
forget someone that you loved.
That being said, it might be
better if, at the very least,
you didn't try to do
things the way she did.
[hair rustling]
Mm!
[RAM]
I see.
It appears you
took care of things,
not a half-bad job either.
My compliments.
[ECHNIDA] Perhaps I'm
overstepping by saying this,
but she was so anxious
for you to return that she
could hardly sit still.
[RAM]
You're right.
You were overstepping.
Learn some restraint, Echidna.
So this is
the attitude you take
the moment you find out I'm
controlling this body instead?
Works for me.
I'll just say it.
I was beside myself with worry,
but I held it in because Subaru
asked me to, I suppose.
Mm.
Mm?
[laughs]
But seriously, Master,
are you sure about this?
Hmm?
[SHAULA]
She tried to merc you.
You're gonna let
her get off scot-free?
Shouldn't she get some kind
of punishment for that?
It's OK.
Meili's already been through
her punishment, I'd say.
Thing is, in the past,
she was punished without
ever knowing the reason.
And things turned out this
way because no one ever
bothered teaching her why.
So from now on, that's my job.
But of course, I'll need
your help to do it right.
[SHAULA]
You want my help?
Yeah, I do.
Everyone in this tower is
gonna be her textbook,
so make sure not to do
anything that would
set a bad example for her.
So then I'm included in this?
Master and me?
Yeah!
[laughs]
[SUBARU]
Uh, what's with you?
Don't worry about it!
Yeah, I'll turn her
into a model citizen.
Just you watch!
Hey, Subaru!
You put weird ideas
in the naked lady's head again,
didn't you?
So she's not
a threat anymore.
Am I understanding that right?
Yep, that's right.
Although it's really
all up to her.
She'll learn from watching our
backs who she wants to become.
So make sure yours
isn't lacking a spine.
I see.
It's simply a matter
of appearances.
All right.
You can count on me.
I expect good things
from you, Mr. Knight.
You and I are the closest thing
she has to a father, after all.
Hmm.
In that case, we'll have
to give it our best.
Hmm.
[laughter]
You know, if I'm going
to be a real big sister
to Meili, then--
[SUBARU] Just a suggestion, but
why not put my amnesia aside
for the time being?
Huh?
Don't get me wrong.
I'm really happy that you want
to help me get my memory back.
Except there's no way anyone
believes this is somehow
unrelated to the tower.
And I'm no exception.
We should assume there's
a connection between this place
and my amnesia, which means--
Which means if we can meet
the requirements to conquer
the tower and all its floors,
we'll likely find the reason
for your amnesia
in the process and maybe
even the key to fixing it.
Is that it?
That's right.
Exactly.
Of course, please don't
take that as me being
OK with staying this way.
I just want to do
what we came here for.
Mm.
I'll be patient, even
though that's hard.
Although--
Huh? What's wrong.
Forgive me, but I can't
help but worry about you more
than anyone else sometimes.
OK?
Uh, sorry.
[sighs]
Emilia just said what
I was going to say, I suppose.
You'd better take
time to reflect.
[SUBARU]
Yeah, you're right.
Well, then, what's
our plan of attack?
So first off,
we need to find a way
to get past the next exam.
And to do that,
we need to figure out
what Reid's weakness is
so we can exploit it
and make it to the next level.
So then, I think the best place
to look would be Reid's book.
Why don't we all
search the archive?
[energetic music and singing]
♪ ♪